akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
Something to Fill the Hole
（ヒナタ）皆さん　力を合わせて
いきますよ！
Everyone! Let's join together
and fight as one!
（みんな）お～！
（ナルト）ヒナタ！
- Right!
Hinata!
（サクラ）あんたは回復！
Time for you to recover!
《みんな…》
You guys...
（マダラ）無駄なことだ。
Such a futile demonstration.
また変化してるぞ。
It's transforming again!
（八尾）いや　ありゃ元に戻ってる
だけだ。
No, it's only reverting
to its original form.
ありゃ　ただの攻撃形態だ。
That was only its attack form.
ただし…。
However...
（八尾）最終変化　一歩手前だ。
It's just one stage away
from its final transformation.
（八尾）ナルトが回復中で
九尾がチャクラ練り込み中だ。
Naruto's still recovering,
and Nine Tails is
infusing chakra right now.
今は　俺らの番だぜ　ビー。
Right now, it's up to us, Bee!
♪♪（キラービー）「そうだ　俺たちが
みんなの操舵」
Right. We'll show everyone the way!
（八尾）よく聞け　ビー。
Listen to me, Bee...
最終変化までさせたら
俺たちの負けだ。
If we let it undergo
its final transformation, we've lost.
ここで…。
We must stop it now!
《マダラ：十尾が手加減なしとは…。
Ten Tails isn't holding back...
ナルトの中に　自分と同じ
尾獣たちを見て焦ったか？》
It probably got impatient
after seeing the same Tailed Beasts
inside Naruto!
楽しみを前にして　一度
バラバラにならざるをえんとはな。
The fun's just beginning,
but it looks like I need to move soon.
（シカマル）どんどん
でかくなってやがるぜ。
It's getting bigger and bigger.
（チョウジ）ナ　ナルトを狙ってる！？
I- Is it after Naruto?
正直　ナルトのチャクラなしで
あれをどうやって…。
Honestly, how're we going
to stop that thing
without Naruto's chakra?
ここへきて　今さら私たちがブレても
どうしようもないでしょ！
We can't waver after
coming this far!
（サクラ）ナルトは　やるべきことを
精一杯やってくれている。
Naruto is putting everything
into doing what has to be done.
((ここに仲間がいねえのが
いちばんいてえんだよ　俺は！))
It's even more painful for me...
not to have any comrades in here!
さっきのナルトの言葉で
はっきりした。
Naruto's words just now
made it clear!
ああ　俺たちみたいな忍でも
ずっと無理して守ってくれてる。
Yeah. He's been going
out of his way
even to protect shinobi like us...
（サクラ）そっちじゃない！
That's not what
I was talking about!
私たちを仲間だと　心底
思い知らせてくれてるってことよ。
He's told us that
he considers all of us his comrades
from the bottom of his heart.
仲間…。
Comrades...
そうだ。
俺たちは…。
- We're...
- That's right, I'm his...
- Me, too...
- That's right, we all are...
俺たちは…。
そうだ。
We all are...
Yeah.
仲間だ。
We're comrades!
Comrades!
仲間だ！
私は　ナルトを全快させる。
I'll fully heal Naruto!
（サクラ）私たちは　私たちの
やるべきことをするのよ！
We have to do
what we have to do!
どうせ死ぬなら　何もしないより→
If we're going to die anyway,
we might as well go down...
自分なりに戦って死ぬ！
fighting to the best of our abilities!
（シカマル）ヘッ　いの！
Ino!
俺とつなげてほしい人がいる。
I want you to link me
with someone!
（いの）なんかあんのね！
さすが　シカマル！
You've got a plan, haven't you?
I knew you would
come through, Shikamaru!
なんとかできねえのかよ！？　親父！
Isn't there anything
we can do, Dad?
チャクラが足りん。
I don't have enough chakra.
Kitsuchi! Please hear me out!
《シカマル：黄ツチさん　聞いてくれ》
《お前は　シカクの子の…》
You're Shikaku's child...
《シカマル：岩隠れの忍以外にもできる
簡単な土遁→
Teach me the signs to
an easy Earth Style Barrier
that even non-Stone Ninja
can perform!
障壁忍術の印を教えてくれ》
《皆がいきなり使える
土遁障壁など→
One that anyone could perform
would be too weak!
たかが知れてるぞ。
それより　もっと…》
It would be better to...
《シカマル：いや　皆ができるってのが
重要なんすよ。
No, it's crucial that
everyone be able to produce it.
向こうが質なら　こっちは量だ》
If the enemy has quality,
we've got quantity.
《それでも
すぐに壁は消し飛ぶぞ》
But these walls will
be blown away quickly.
Even if they are
《消し飛ばされても　そのあとから
次々作り続ければ盾になる。
if we keep creating more,
they'll act like a shield.
強い壁で止めるというより
弱い壁で勢いを殺し続ける。
We're going to slow
that thing's momentum
with many weak walls rather than
try to stop it with one powerful one!
もちろん　岩隠れの皆さんには→
Of course, I intend to have
all of you from the Hidden Stone
すげえ壁を作ってもらう
つもりっすけど》
build me a super wall as well...
《なるほど。　やってみる価値は
あるかもしれんな。
I see... Your idea might be
worth a try.
よし　印を教えよう》
All right,
these are the hand signs!
《シカマル：その前に　ビーさんだ。
Before we start...
Master Bee!
皆で壁を作り続けている間に
できるだけ尾獣玉をぶつけて→
While everyone is
building barriers,
I want you to bombard that thing
with Tailed Beast Bombs
あれの軌道を上へ変えてほしい》
to shift its trajectory upwards.
いの。
Ino...
Next, I want you to link me
次は俺と　この戦場にいる
すべての忍をつなげてくれ。
with every shinobi here
on the battlefield.
できるか？
できるかじゃなくて　やるのよ！
Can you do it?
Doesn't matter, I will do it!
（オビト）
幻術の世界の何が問題なんだ？
What's your issue with
a Genjutsu World?
現実は残酷だ。
この穴が広がるだけでしかない。
Reality is cruel.
This hole is only going to get bigger.
思い通りに
事が運ばないこともあれば→
Things don't always
go the way you want them.
助けが間に合わないこともある。
Nor does help always
get there in time.
俺がそうだったように。
Just like how it was with me!
俺が間に合わなかったように！
Just like how I couldn't
get there in time!
なぁ　そうだろ　カカシ。
Wouldn't you agree, Kakashi?
こんな世界にいて
どうやってこの穴を埋める？
How are you going to seal
this hole by staying in this world?!
（カカシ）俺は忍のクズだが
それでも学んだことがある。
I may be trash as a shinobi,
but I've learned a few things.
心の穴は他のみんなが
埋めてくれるもんなんだよ。
The hole in one's heart gets filled
by others around you.
自分の都合通りにいかないからと
仲間の思いまで捨てて→
Friends won't flock to
someone who abandons
the memory of his friends
and gives up on the world...
この世界を諦めているやつに
仲間なんか集まりはしないよ。
Just because things don't go
the way he wants them to.
それじゃ
心の穴も埋まりはしない。
That won't help fill
the hole in your heart.
逃げて何もしないやつに
人は何もしてくれないしな。
And people don't help those
who run away and do nothing.
諦めなきゃ　必ず救いがある。
As long as you don't give up,
there will always be salvation.
何をしようとも…。
No matter what you do...
終わりだ。
It's over.
（みんな）土遁障壁！
- Earth Style Barrier!
（八尾）来たぞ　ビー！
（キラービー）いくぜ！
Here it comes, Bee!
Let's go!
威力がケタ違いだ！
Its power is off the charts!
クッ！
《思ったより強いぞ
このままでは…》
It's more powerful than I thought.
At this rate...
《最後の障壁が…》
The last barrier...!
ビー様！
Lord Bee!
きれい事をグダグダと。
All your tedious whitewashing!
One can only achieve true happiness
by abandoning reality
現実を…　この世界の仲間との
思いを捨てきってこそ→
and ridding yourself of
the memories of your comrades!
本当の幸せがある。
忍の世界で　ルールや掟を破るやつは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
In the ninja world, those who
break the rules are scum.
けどな→
But... those who abandon
their friends are worse than scum.
仲間を大切にしないやつは
それ以上のクズだ。
そして　仲間の思いを
大切にしないやつは→
And... those who don't care
about their friends' feelings...
更に　それ以上のクズだ。
are even worse scum!
（キラービー）クッ…　ウウッ…。
んん！？
消えた？
It vanished...?
（カカシ）かつてのお前の思いを
捨てないよ…。
I won't abandon my memory
of the old you.
それを否定するのが
今のお前でも。
Even if it's the current you
who's repudiating it.
（ミナト）遅かったか？
Am I late?
いや　ピッタリだぜ　父ちゃん。
Nope.
Right on time, Dad!
FOURTH HOKAGE
Who...?
えっ？　誰が　誰の？
Who's...?
My name's Minato Namikaze.
俺は波風ミナト。　爆発に備えて。
Brace for an impending explosion.
あっ。
What is that?
何だ？
何？
What?
I sent Ten Tails' attack
back toward the sea.
十尾の攻撃を
海へ飛ばしたからだよ。
うわぁ！
何だ？
攻撃か！？
- What's that?!
- Is it an attack?!
Watch out!
危ない！
What the hell's going on?!
何がどうなってる！？
あっ！
うわっ　何だ…。
What just happened?!
That shock wave came
out of nowhere!
もういきなり　あさっての方向から
衝撃波　こんなのあり！？
What's with that?!
Stop complaining!
文句言うな！
こんなもんで済んでラッキーだぜ。
We're lucky that
we got off that easily!
（サクラ）あっ。
He has Reanimation eyes!
《穢土転生の眼》
Wh-Who are you?
あ　あなたは？
安心して。
キミたちの味方だよ。
Relax. I'm an ally.
Thanks for healing Naruto!
ナルトを回復してくれて
ありがとう。
Are you...
キミは…　ナルトの彼女かな？
Naruto's girlfriend?
Huh?
ん？　う～ん。
Hmm...
Uh-huh... Yeah!
うん　うんうんうん
まあ　そんな感じ！
I suppose you could say that.
You keep quiet!
あんたは黙ってなさい！
しゃべる体力も温存！
Don't waste your energy talking!
ウッ　グクッ…　回復どころか→
You're supposed to be healing me,
but I just suffered more damage...
ダメージくらってんだけどもよ。
I'll heal the extra damage too!
（サクラ）その分　割り増しで
回復したげるわよ。
アッハッハッハ…。
《クシナに少し似てるかな　この子》
She reminds me a little of Kushina...
息子をお手柔らかに願います。
Please go easy on my son.
So, why did this happen so suddenly?
ねえ　急になんでこんなことに？
It seems like you knew.
あんた　知ってたみたいだけど。
ああ　九尾モードで
チャクラを感知してたんだ。
I sensed his chakra when
I was in Nine Tails Mode.
The others should be arriving soon...
そろそろ他にも。
あっ　何か来る。
Something's coming!
Minato, you're as fast as ever!
ミナト　相変わらず速いの。
さ　三代目火影様　それに→
Lord Third Hokage?!
And also...
That's the...!
これって…。
Fourth...
（扉間）四代目　貴様
わし以上の瞬身使いよの。
You're better
at teleporting than I am!
All right, let's do this!
（柱間）ようし　始めるぞ。
No way!
まさか。
信じられない。
I don't believe it...
初代様　二代目様→
Lords First...
Second...
Third...
それに三代目様→
and even Lord Fourth...
四代目　ミナト様まで。
Minato!
So you're the ones
who stopped the attack, Lords Hokage!
そうか　さっきの攻撃を
止めてくれたのは　火影様たち。
But who reanimated you?
しかし　いったい誰が穢土転生を？
Orochimaru summoned us.
大蛇丸がわしらを呼んだのじゃ。
We need to stop this war quickly.
さっさと　この戦争を止めねばな。
What? Didn't Orochimaru die?
え？　大蛇丸って死んだんじゃ。
This is amazing!
すごい　先代たちが
共に戦ってくれるのか！
The previous Hokage are going
to join us in battle!
Now that's reassuring!
それは心強い！
I don't know
what's going on anymore...
もう　何が何だか。
There's still more help coming,
まだまだ増援いるんだけども→
but they're taking a little longer.
ちょい遅れてるみてえだな。
I've been waiting for you, Hashirama!
待っていたぞ　柱間！
I'll deal with you later!
お前は　あと。
あっ…。
I have to stop
the Ten Tails first!
まずは　十尾を止める。
フッ　相変わらずなやつだ。
He hasn't changed a bit.
やはり　あいつとは　かみ合わん。
We're never on the same page.
After all...
だって　こっち走ってきてるし。
It's charging towards us...
You've done well, Naruto.
ナルト　よくやってくれたね。
Take a little break.
少し休んでなさい。
友達も　じきに来る。
Your friend will be here soon.
He's our ally too.
（ミナト）彼も味方だよ。
He is?
《あいつが》
This presence...
《九喇嘛：この気配
ミナトのやつ　これは》
It's Minato... What's going on?
My fellow Hokage, let's go!
火影たち　行くぞ。
えっ。
Second and Third,
stand in front of me.
二代目　三代目　私の前へ。
《これって　ナルトと同じ？》
That's exactly like Naruto's...
まさかとは思ったが　ミナトまで。
I never imagined
Minato would too!
See! You see!
なっ　なっ！
俺の父ちゃんてば　すげえだろ？
Isn't my dad awesome?!
I know that better than you!
そんなことは
お前より　わかっとる。
Reaper Death Seal!
((屍鬼封尽！
Let's put our trust in this child!
（ミナト）この子を信じよう。
He's our son, after all!
なんたって
俺たちの息子なんだから。
Seal!
(封印))
After all, he's the one who
split me up before sealing me away!
このわしを分けてでも
封印しきった男だ。
THIRD HOKAGE
Have you already placed
your markers?
すでにマーキングはしたのか？
はい。
Yes.
You're quick at striking too!
先手を打つのも早いのう。
He vanished!
消えた？
Let's go!
行くぞ　忍法…。
Ninja Art...
（４人）四赤陽陣。
- Four Crimson Ray Formation!
And... I'll just add on...
更に俺だけ加えての…。
Sage Art: Gracious Deity Gates!
仙法　明神門。
Ten Seals!
（柱間）封十。
A red barrier?!
（リー）赤い結界？
It's said to be dozens of times
more powerful
（ガイ）あれが四紫炎陣の何十倍も
強いという→
than the Four Purple
Flames Formation!
火影クラスの忍が
４人いないとできん結界だ。
It's a barrier that requires
four Hokage-class shinobi
together to create!
It won't be able to move
so easily now.
（柱間）これで
そう簡単には動けん。
えっ。
You sure took your time
getting here, Sasuke.
ずいぶん遅かったじゃねえの　サスケ。
Sasu... ke?
（サクラ）サスケ君？
（サスケ）サクラか。
Is that you, Sakura?
S-Sasuke! Why?!
サ　サスケ君。
《なんで？》
（３人）あっ。
（２人）あっ。
（ヒナタ）あっ。
S-Sasuke!
サ　サスケ君。
Hey, Ino! Stop!
おい　いの　止まれ！
こいつは敵だぞ！
He's an enemy!
Ino... You better keep your distance!
いの　うかつに
近づかないほうが　いいよ。
You're all still as noisy as ever!
相変わらず　やかましいやつらだ。
（赤丸）ワン！　ワン！
Why the hell are you here, bastard?!
（キバ）てめえ　何しに来やがった！
なんで　サスケ君がここに？
Why are you here, Sasuke?
A lot of things have happened.
いろいろあったが　俺は
木ノ葉の里を守ることに決めた。
I've decided to protect Leaf Village.
And then, I'll...
そして　俺が。
become Hokage.
火影になる。
What?!
え～！？
You can't just come back
all of a sudden
ご無沙汰　抜け忍が
いきなり帰ってきて→
and crack a lame joke like that,
you Rogue Ninja!
ギャグかましてんじゃねえぞ！
Do you even know
what it means to be Hokage?
火影の意味　わかってんのか　ゴラァ！
I don't know what happened to you,
but that's not possible.
お前に何があったか知らねえが
ありえねえんだよ　そんなこと。
Do you even realize
what you're saying?
お前　自分が何言ってんのか。
Do you think we can just forget
all the things you've done?
（シノ）今までのことが
チャラにできると思っているのか。
Yeah, I realize you probably can't.
ああ　チャラにはできないだろう。
But...
だが　お前らが　俺のことを
どう思うかは　関係ない。
it doesn't matter
what you guys think of me.
All of the previous Kage created
these current circumstances.
今までの影たちが
この状況を作った。
So I will become Hokage
and change the village.
だから
俺が火影になり　里を変える。
You don't become Hokage
((イタチ：火影になった者が
皆に認められるんじゃない。
in order to be acknowledged
by the village.
The one who is acknowledged
by everyone,
皆から認められた者が
火影になるんだ。
is the one who becomes Hokage.
I leave Sasuke to you.
(サスケは　お前に任せる))
Leave it to me.
《任せておけ》
I'm going to be Hokage!
火影になるのは　俺だってばよ！
I'm glad there's so much interest
in becoming Hokage...
そんなに火影に
憧れてくれるのは　嬉しいが→
But you guys are
taking too much time!
お前ら　ゆっくりしすぎぞ！
Start infusing chakra right now!
今のうちに　チャクラを練れ。
一斉攻撃で　あれを倒す！
We'll take down Ten Tails
with an all-out attack!
Thanks for healing me, Sakura!
サクラちゃん　回復ありがとう。
Now it's your turn to get some rest.
今度は　サクラちゃんが　休んでくれ
行くぞ　サスケ！
Let's go, Sasuke!
ん？
Sakura?
サクラちゃん？
私が　２人に届かない→
So do you see me as
some sort of weak woman
who can't keep up with you two?
か弱い女だと思ってる？
Do you think Lady Tsunade
would be the only one
三忍の綱手様だけ→
out of the Legendary Sannin
to inadequately train her student?
弟子の鍛え方が
下手なわけないでしょ。
（サクラ）もう少しなの
もう少しで溜まりきる。
I'm almost there...
I'll be at full capacity in a little bit.
Then I can output my true power.
（サクラ）本当の力が　やっと出せる。
Just like you,
I'm a member of Team 7...
私だって　第七班
そして　三忍の弟子の一人。
and I'm a student of
one of the Legendary Sannin!
フッ　よっしゃ！
Okay then!
Team 7 is finally back!
第七班　ここに復活だってばよ！
Let's go, Sakura! Sasuke!
行くぜ　サクラちゃん　サスケ！
Right!
うん。
おう。
Yeah!
That sight sure brings
back memories, doesn't it, Shikamaru?
なんか　懐かしい画じゃない？
シカマル。
Well, if he's willing to
help us defeat the enemy,
どうあれ　目の前の敵を倒すのに
協力するってんなら→
I won't turn him away.
今は　しかたねえ
認めたくはねえが。
Even tho' I don't want to accept him...
It's been a long time since
our class has been back together.
同期が全員　揃うのって
久しぶりだよね。
I haven't felt like this
since the Chunin Exam.
この感じも　中忍試験以来だし。
I'm going to become Hokage!
火影になんのは　俺だ！
ちょっ　お前ら　聞いてんのか！
Hey, are you guys even listening?!
Kiba, no one's paying attention right now...
and it's pitiful.
キバ　今は誰も聞いていない。
惨めに見える　よせ。
Stop it.
It's because the impact of
Sasuke's sudden appearance
なぜなら　いきなり出てきて
「火影になる」とのたまった→
and his declaration to
become Hokage are much too great.
サスケのインパクトのほうが
強すぎるからだ。
キバ君　私はちゃんと聞いてるよ。
Kiba, I heard you!
We should all aspire
to become Hokage!
火影は
みんなが目指すものだもんね。
ワン！　ワン！
Let's show them
what we're made of, ya know!
俺らの力　見せてやるってばよ！
koushite ima mo kawarazu
Even now, I haven't changed
donna tsuyoi nami ni mo sakarau
I'll fight any wave, no matter how strong it is
soko ni wa nakama, haruka kanata
My friends are far away
deatta subete ga ore no takara
Everyone I meet is my treasure
kono sora e habataiteku
I'll fly through this sky
ore kara shinjiru anata ni eeru
I believe in you and I'll yell out to you
toki ni wa warai naite
Sometimes I laugh or cry
donna ni fumareyouto hana wa saiteru
The flowers still bloom,
no matter how many times they've been trampled on
datte kimetakara
It's because I've made up my mind
donna ni fumarete mo saiteta hana
I'll rise up like a blooming flower
no you ni motto takaku
No matter how many times it gets trampled
sore ga naniyori mo chikara hanatsu
It unleashes more power than anything
aitsu no bun made tsuyoku ikite
I want to live resiliently for their sake too
dare ni mo makenai tsuyoi ishide
With a powerful will, I won't give in to anyone
susume kitto susumeru
Move ahead, I'm sure I'll move ahead
dare mo mitakotonai sekai wo tsukureru
I can create a world that no one has seen before
kowakunai soba ni iru kagiri
I'm not afraid, as long as you're by my side
mawari ni wa nakama ya famirii
Surrounded by friends and family
sono chikara ga michishirube ni naru
Their power shows me the way
minna kara moratta kono te ni love
In my hand, I hold what everyone has given me Love
kono machi ni fuku kaze ni noru
I'll ride the wind that blows through this city
gooru wa mada hodo tooku
I'm still a long way from my goal
demo shitteru mada yare n datte
But I know that I can still go on
dakara sakebu kono koe kareru made
So I'll cry out until I lose my voice
kono sekai wa mienu mono bakari de
This world is full of things I can't see
kowai kara jibunjishin wo kizutsuketa
I hurt myself because I was afraid of them
kirisaita yami no saki ni mieta mono
When I cut through the darkness, I saw something
massugu ni misueta mama de
I continue to gaze straight ahead
hanasanai
And never let go
Ever since I was a genin,
I thought I was
a full-fledged kunoichi.
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
But I ended up hiding
behind Sasuke and Naruto.
I hated the way I was.
I swore then, that next time,
豆助　きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のあれよ
I would make them
stare at my back!
And now finally, I...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Team 7 Assemble!"
＜　その野菜とは…＞
Shannaro!
＜　それは…＞